# **RAVI** SUHAG

suhag.ravi@gmail.com . +919717860747

Engineering and product leader with a passion for building great products. More than 10 years of experience in building and leading high-impact engineering teams. Proven track record to establish a vision and execute efficiently. Active contributor and maintainer of open-source projects.

#### **EXPERTISE**

## **Team Building**

Recognizing and attracting top-tier members. Coach and guide teams through their strengths and weaknesses with regular feedback.

#### **Data Engineering**

Experience in building distributed real-time data pipelines that can handle billions of data points per day.

#### **Data Analytics**

Experience in building tools to visualize and analyse big data in an effective, understandable & engaging manner.

#### **Distributed Systems**

Experience in developing distributed, fault-tolerant backend and frontend systems using the latest technology and modern frameworks.

### **Product Development**

Track record on driving product development with influence that meaningfully moves the business forward.

# **Product Design**

Designing user-centered, clean, and functional products that follow structure, simplicity, visibility, and reuse.

# **Partnership**

Establish strong relationships with both business and technical leaders across and outside organisation.

# Vision

Understanding business, analytics, and technology, to guide teams by providing relevant context and inspiration.

# **RECOGNITION**

Featured by TedX, Quartz, Scroll, Josh Talks, Angel Hack and other organizations for winning a series of hackathons organised by Sequoia, President of India, Embassy of Netherlands, Nasscom, Times Group and more.

# **CONTACT**

Website www.ravisuhag.com
Linkedin linkedin.com/in/ravisuhag
Github github.com/ravisuhag

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Founder**

Jan 2021 - Present

**Open DataOps Foundation** 

Leading vision and community efforts to build open-source, collaborative, and distributed data platform to power data-driven workflows. ODPF provides a consistent and unified platform for data lifecycle, data management, data integrity, and data governance to magnify developer productivity. (http://github.com/odpf)

#### **VP Engineeering**

Jan 2017 - Present

Gojek

Leading product and engineering efforts to build large-scale, self-service data platforms including Enterprise Data Platform, Experimentation Platform, Analytics Platform, and Customer Data Platform. These platforms empower the Gojek workforce to make data-driven decisions.

## **Engineering Lead**

Apr 2014 - Mar 2017

**Harvard Kennedy School of Government** 

Lead technology efforts to design and develop data interfaces for evidence-based policy decisions and increasing accountability in public programs. Developed high-potential pilot projects which demonstrate the value of data and evidence through hands-on capacity building, while simultaneously creating innovative and effective ways for policy actors to utilize data and research evidence to improve their decision-making.

## Consultant

Apr 2015 - Dec 2015

JPAL, MIT

Built data exploration framework for emission trading system to enable the Ministry of Environment & Forests to cap total pollution emissions in selected areas and increase regulatory transparency and accountability.

# Founder.

June 2010 - Dec 2015

**Inspiration Edge** 

Design-driven software company working with ambitious people and organizations to provide software delivery, pioneering tools and consulting in commercial, social, educational and government sectors.

# **Embedded Developer**

May 2009 - June 2010

Appin Technology

Designed and implemented software for microcontrollers and arduino based embedded devices and systems. Delivered training and workshops on fundamentals of embedded systems.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Technology**

Major in Electronics and communication engineering from KIIT College of Engineering.